NYSUT Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Files 6174/008
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Mt. Sinai, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  Competing organizing materials by Federation of Nurses/UFT and New York State Nurses Association (NYSNA); update memos from NYSUT's John O'Leary
- North Westchester Hospital Center, 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  List of RNs signing FNHP-NYSUT cards; signed cards; handwritten lists of names, by department; FNHP fact sheet; pro-union flyers; case before the NLRB; anti-union correspondence from management
- NY Hospital (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Telephone message slip
- OR Nurses Association (Box 3, Folder 2)
  List of operating room nurses, city-wide
- Oswego Con. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Newspaper clipping re organizing efforts at Oswego Hospital by Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals; organizing flyer
- Phelps Memorial Hospital Center (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Recruiting materials
- Philippine Nurses Association, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Flyer for fundraising event for education fund; letter from NYSUT general counsel James Sandner to clinical research nurse at Mt. Sinai Hospital re right of non-citizen RNs to join unions
- Poughkeepsie Registered Nurses, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Agreement between Poughkeepsie City School District and Poughkeepsie Public School Paraprofessionals, July 1, 1983-June 30, 1985; Poughkeepsie City School District Registered Nurses Salary and Benefits; Paraprofessional Salary Schedule 1984-85; Registered Professional Nurse Salary Schedule: BOE [Board of Education] Adopted 6/25/86
- Richmond County Nurses Ass., 1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Articles from White Collar Report re contract agreements between nurse unions and hospitals
- St. Luke's-Roosevelt Hospital Center, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Collective bargaining election petition; blank employment application; description of St. Luke's-Roosevelt Hospital Center; note to FNHP organizer Lynn Duggan from Dr. Mary Belmont referencing article; Belmont resume
- Staten Island, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  Article from White Collar Report re end of strike at Staten Island Hospital by NYS Nurses' Association, ratification of contract at St. Vincent's
- SEIU, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Articles from White Collar Report re end of strike by Service Employees International Union (SEIU) Local 200 at Columbia Memorial Hospital, acceptance of contract at Crouse-Irving Memorial Hospital, and acceptance of contract by Local 144 with NY League of Voluntary Hospitals and Homes
- Strong Memorial Hospital, 1985-1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Correspondence from management to nursing staff with questions and answers re union activity, salary increases; newspaper clippings
- Hospital for Special Surgery (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Recruitment materials, including salary figures
- St. Vincent's NYC (Greenwich Village), 1983 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Recruiting brochures; job descriptions
- St. Vincent's Richmond (Staten Island), 1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Federation of Nurses/UFT folder with organizing report form by Lynn Duggan; description of pension plan; job descriptions; lists of names; St. Vincent's Guidelines for Department Heads and Supervisors re policy re union organizing (why facility did not need a union); nurse recruitment packet; "welcome" folder re employee benefits
- North Shore, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Letter to organizers from NYSUT director of organizing John O'Leary re court decision on supervisors in New York State Nurses Association (NYSNA) NLRB vs North Shore University Hospital; official notice to employees, posted on order of the NLRB; text of federal and state court decisions involving labor relations; Organizing Bulletin by NYSUT Division of Field Services re court-ordered restructuring of NYSNA
- Syosset (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Newspaper clipping; application for membership/authorization card for Local 144, SEIU, Registered Nurses Guild
- Westchester Med. Center, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Lists of members of CSEA and Federation of Health Professionals; newsletter of Federation of Nurses/UFT, House Calls; recruiting brochures for Westchester County Medical Center and Ruth Taylor Geriatric and Rehabilitation Institute
- Visiting Nurse Service of New York (VNS), 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Annual reports, 1982 and 1983; recruiting materials; agreement between Visiting Nurse Service of New York and Federation of Nurses/UFT, January 1, 1981-January 31, 1983, and February 1, 1983-January 31, 1985; contract with Lutheran Medical Center, effective January 1, 1983; newsletters; articles from White Collar Report
- Yonkers VNS Westchester (1 of 2), 1981-1987 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  VNS annual report and financial summary to NYS Department of State; Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals profile of organizing activity; excerpts of Public Health Law; correspondence re organizing campaign
- Yonkers VNS Westchester (2 of 2), 1986-1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Authorization cards; Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals newsletters; tally of ballots; agreement between NYS Nurses Association and Visiting Nurse Services in Westchester, Inc., December 16, 1983-December 15, 1986; agreement between Westchester Federation of Visiting Nurses and Visiting Nurse Services in Westchester, Inc., December 16, 1986-December 15, 1989; NLRB recertification petition; constitution
- United Hospital Port Chester (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Application for employment; descriptive materials for hospital, Department of Nursing new graduate orientation program, staff nurse salary and benefits
- NYU Medical Center (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Recruiting materials for New York University Medical Center and NYU Institute of Rehabilitation Medicine
- Vassar Brothers Hospital, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  White Collar Report articles, newspaper clippings re strike, settlement
- Yonkers General Hospital, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  Brochure; RN salary sheet; application for employment
- Federal Service Labor-Management Relations Statute, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Agreement between Veterans Administration Medical Center, Brooklyn, NY, and New York State Nurses Association; contract summary; printed booklets of statute; Guide to the Federal Service Labor-Management Relations Statute; Rules and Regulations of the Federal Labor Relations Authority, General Counsel of the Federal Labor Relations Authority and Federal Service Impasses Panel, revised as of January 1, 1983; booklet, Nursing Careers in the Veterans Administration; employee handbook; handwritten notes indicating "no hope for this group," "do not want union"
- White Plains Hospital (Box 3, Folder 26)
  Recruiting brochures
- VA Hospital Rules, 1975-1984 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  Printed booklet, Federal Service Labor-Management Relations Statute; agreement between Veterans Administration Medical Center, Brooklyn, NY, and New York State Nurses Association; Veterans Administration Hospital agreement, Massachusetts Nurses Association, effective August 29, 1975; Negotiated Agreement between Veterans Administration Hospital, Des Moines, Iowa, and Iowa Nurses' Association; 1982 Agreement between Veterans Administration Medical Center, Wood, Wisconsin, and VA Staff Nurses Council, Local 5032, AFT, AFL-CIO, with cover memo to Lynn Duggan, FNHP/NYSUT, July 5, 1984; booklet, Nurse Careers in the Veterans Administration; booklet, Who Cares Enough: Public Health Service Nurses; booklet, VA Nursing; Federal Labor Relations Authority petition; Federal Register text of Federal Labor Relations Authority, General Counsel of the Federal Labor Relations Authority; and Federal Service Impasses Panel, January 17, 1980; materials from the Wisconsin Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Veterans Administration Staff Nurses Council, with cover letter re organizing campaign from council president to NYSUT director of field services Jim Conti, July 24, 1980
- Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Letterheads (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Blank stationery with NYSUT and FNHP letterhead
- Healthcare Education, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  State Education Department Nursing Handbook, July 1986; NYS Public Employment Relations Board Rules of Procedure 1984; AFL-CIO Industrial Union Department booklet, "The Inside Game: Winning with Workplace Strategies," 1986; memo from NYSUT organizing director John O'Leary re nurses' views on the concept of nurse practitioners, July 1, 1987; National Education Association 1986-87 Leadership Handbook, "Excellence: Working for You"; organizing materials for FNHP; newspaper clippings
- Letters, 1979-1982 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  Correspondence from FNHP nurse organizer Lynn Duggan and others re organizing campaign and related issues
- Organizing, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  Booklet by NYS Public Employment Relations Board, "The Taylor Law," 1987-88; materials by Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals, "Conflict Resolution" and fact sheet, "Why FNHP/NYSUT"; AFL-CIO National Organizing Coordinating Committee newsletters, "Report on Union Busters: RUB Sheet" and "S.T.I.R.: Statistical and Tactical Information Report"
- Staff Meeting, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  Agenda and memo to organizers from NYSUT organizing director John O'Leary; newsletter of the NYSUT Division of Field Services, "Organizing Bulletin"; Daily Labor Report article re NLRB ruling that religious schools were not subject to the NLRA; NEA-NY Official Report of the Secretary-Treasurer, Eleventh Annual Delegate Assembly; confidential report on the Delegate Assembly by NYSUT operative; PERB decisions; article reprints; Labor Department rules on reasonable assurance of return to employment; organizing plan for 1987 and 1988
- Agency Fee, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  Suggested model for agency fee rebate procedures for the 1983-84 fiscal year, with cover letter to local presidents
- ALCU (Box 3, Folder 34)
  Description of ACLU handbook, "The Rights of Teachers"
- BOCES III, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Letter from school nurse at BOCES III (Suffolk), asking for more information about FNHP/NYSUT, with attached newspaper clipping
- CE's Burn Trauma (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Self-assessment form for emergency management of burn trauma, with answer key; handwritten notes
- Cadex (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Bellevue Hospital Center Medical-Surgical Specialties Nursing Care Standards; assessment and discharge forms
- Citations-FNHP, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Citation certificates for service "to the cause of health care unionism"; NYSUT memo
- Applications (Charter) FNHP, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Application forms for new and continuing local charters
- Clip Art (Box 4, Folder 6)
  NYSUT clip art book of NYSUT logos, half tones, and other camera-ready art; FNHP logos and other line drawings
- Constitution, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Sample constitution for locals affiliated with NYSUT
- Computer Workshop, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Material for NYSUT Information Management Systems Committee re salary schedule costout software
- Contracts, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  White Collar Report (Bureau of National Affairs) articles re contract agreements between nursing unions and various hospitals
- DUE, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Letter to DUE members from NYSUT president Tom Hobart, urging reconsideration of decision to disaffiliate, noting NYSUT's work for community college faculty members, with attached newspaper clipping re lobbying efforts to increase aid
- Department of Labor-Smoking Policy, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Memorandum of Understanding between National Council of Field Labor Locals and Department of Labor re smoking policy
- Department for Professional Employees AFL-CIO, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Newsletter, Interface, published quarterly by the Department for Professional Employees, AFL-CIO, featuring article, "Employment in the health services industry: Where it's been and where it's going"
- DRG (Diagnosis Related Group), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Articles on the effect on nursing of DRGs for Medicare reimbursement, including article, "What Nurses Should Know about DRGs"
- Dues, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Letter to local presidents from NYSUT secretary-treasurer Herb Magidson re dues structure for 1984-85 membership year; article re linking dues to salaries
- Empire Plan, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  NYSUT Information Bulletin re the Empire Plan (NYS health insurance)
- FNHP Advisory, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Brochures for Nurse Professional Issues Conference, "AIDS: What the health care professional should know," June 14, 1986; post-tests by attendees; certificates of continuing education; FNHP Handbook on Cost Containment; health care resolutions, 1983 and 1984 AFT conventions
- FNHP, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  Folder of public relations material, with cover letter to local leaders, March 16, 1987; publication by AFL-CIO Department for Professional Employees, "The Health Services Industry in the United States: Trends in Employment from 1970 to 1983 with Projections to 1995," by Ed Sekscenski, August 1984; publication by National Council on Aging National Citizens' Board of Inquiry into Health in America, "Health Care USA: 1984, volume I: The National Report"; FNHP Health Care Organizer's Kit: the Law, the Techniques, the Issues; clip art for use on FNHP material; FNHP brochures; correspondence
- FNHP Flyers, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  Organizing flyers
- FNHP Poster, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  Poster; Healthwire newsletter; Update newsletter
- Federal Mediation and Health Care, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Booklet, "Rx for Labor Peace: Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service and its role in the health care industry: A handbook"; case study, "To Strike or Not to Strike?" Journal of Christian Nursing; memo from NYSUT organizing director John O'Leary to organizers re required forms to be filed at impasse in private sector negotiations, December 9, 1985
- Flyers (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Organizing flyers by Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals
- Great Neck Library, 1984-1988 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  Agreements between Great Neck Library and Great Neck Library Staff Association/Part-Time Staff Association, June 1984; proposed amendment language; handwritten notes; NYSUT organizing flyers
- Handicapped, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  Organizing material; copy of document from State Education Department, "Reimbursable Cost Manual for Private Schools Receiving Funding under Article 89 and Article 81 of Education Law to Educate Handicapped Children, " September 1884; list of 853 Schools within NYS; list of participating agencies in NYS Health Insurance Program; NYSUT Information Bulletin re BOCES 1984-85 estimated per-student cost; letter to NYSUT local presidents re organizing campaign at schools and agencies for the handicapped, with attached list, October 28
- Glossary Health Care Terms (Box 4, Folder 24)
  Glossary of Select Terms in Health Care Facilities, by Retail Clerks International Association, May 1975; list of standard abbreviations for work areas, measurements, time intervals
- Hospital Professionals and Allied Employees (HPAE) of NJ, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  HPAE constitution and by-laws, with cover letter to FNHP organizer Lynn Duggan; list of staff members at Wayne General; letters to staff from organizing committee
- Third Party Insurance Law, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  Signing statement from Gov. Mario Cuomo, approving of bill permitting certification of for- profit home health agencies; text of bill in Assembly
- Improper Practice (IP) Workshop, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  Booklet, "Mandatory/Nonmandatory Subjects of Negotiation," March 1985; NYS PERB booklets, "Rules of Procedure 1984" and "The Taylor Law, 1983-84"; memo re cases used in workshop; outline, Elements of an I.P.; handwritten notes
- Job Injury, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  Booklets from NYS Workers' Compensation Board, "On the Job Injury," "Off the Job Injury," and "Rehabilitation Questions and Answers"; memo to NYSUT regional office staff re State Education Department publication, "Annual Educational Summary 1982-83"
- City RNs (Box 4, Folder 29)
  Floppy disk
- CPMC (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Lincoln Hall, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Authorization cards for representation by Lincoln Hall Faculty Association, returned to NYSUT by the National Labor Relations Board, with cover letter; Request for Review of Regional Director's Decision; Petitioner's Statement in Opposition to Employer's Request for Review of Regional Director's Decision; Post Hearing Brief on behalf of Petitioner; related briefs; Lincoln Hall 1987 Annual Report; 1986-87 Median Salaries of Special Education Teachers, October 1987; correspondence, including letter from management to employees, April 6, 1987
- Labor Law, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Document, "The Reagan Administration's Record on Labor Law Issues," with cover letter from AFL-CIO general counsel
- Meany Center, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Course catalogs
- NLRB Election, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  NLRB instructions to election observers; NLRB computer printouts for NYS hospital elections from July 1961 to December 1982, with cover letter to NYSUT director of organizing John O'Leary; representation decisions
- State Education Nursing, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  State Education Department Office of the Professions Nursing Education Unit update memorandum
- Nursing Life, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Letter to NYSUT field representative Lynn Duggan from special correspondent for Nursing Life re interview, with copy of May/June 1986 issue of Nursing Life; follow-up letter from correspondent; March/April 1987 issue
- NYCOSH (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Job safety and health publications list of the New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health; Bill of Rights: NYS Right-to-Know Laws; flyer by NYS AFL-CIO, "The Truth about Coors"
- Mid Atlantic, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Document, "Profile of Health/Nursing Personnel and Resources in the Mid-Atlantic Region," compiled by Mid-Atlantic Nursing Association, with cover letter from FNHP
- Phone Survey, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Phone survey script; Final Report on Onondaga County Nurse Survey; NYSUT Information Bulletin re opinions of teachers on education reform issues; survey questions
- Survey Outline-Health and Hospitals Corporation, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  RN survey questions; Opinion Forecast Telephone Survey on Voting Preference of Registered Nurses in the New York City Health and Hospitals Corporation System; information for interviewers
- Wilson Phone Survey, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Wilson Hospital Nurses Survey, July 1983; summary of survey results (published in NYSUT Information Bulletin); draft, Telephone Survey on Union-Voting Preference of Registered Nurses in New York City's Health and Hospitals Corporation System: Summary of Survey Results, October 1983
- NLRB (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Document by Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals, AFT, AFL-CIO, "The National Labor Relations Act: A Guide for Organizers"
- NYSUT's Health Care Policies, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Chronological list, " NYSUT Policies Relative to Health Care or Health Care Professions" (adopted by Board of Directors or Representative Assembly)
- Health Care Resolutions, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  AFT health care resolutions adopted from 1979 to 1983, and proposed at 1984 convention, whether adopted or defeated, with cover letter to NSYUT organizing Director John O'Leary
- Regents Report Cards, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Confidential reports to NYSUT Board and staff, "Regents' Report Card," reporting on actions taken by the State Education Department's Board of Regents, prepared by NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services
- Right to Work States, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Article clipping from AFL-CIO News, "Average income lowest in 'right-to-work' states," December 8, 1984
- Resolutions, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  Implementation of Resolutions Adopted by the 1984 Representative Assembly (NYSUT)
- State Education Department Licensing Services, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  State Education Department Candidate Handbook: Nursing; SED newsletter, Nursing Education News; U.S. Department of Health and Human Services announcement re application for nursing research grants
- St. Francis Hospital, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  Brief before the NLRB, St. Francis Hospital, employer, and International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local Union 474, AFL-CIO (decision on review and direction); articles from Labor Relations Week; memo to organizers from NYSUT organizing director John O'Leary re Court of Appeals reversal of NLRB decision in St. Francis
- Time Management, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  Participant's workbook, "How to Get Control of Your Time and Your Job"; NYSUT Time Management newsletter
- Update, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  Newsletters by Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals re St. Francis case and other NLRB decisions
- W4 Forms, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  Employee's Withholding Allowance Certificate, Withholding Exemption Certificate, and NYS/NYC withholding exemption certificate
- FNHP Clip Art (Box 5, Folder 23)
  Camera-ready logos
- Fed Literature, 1981-1983 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  American Nurse Association survey, with cover letter to organizers from NYSUT organizing director John O'Leary, July 19, 1983; American Nurses Association materials re need for lobbying action re appropriations, changes in Medicare/Medicaid requirements for participating hospitals; New York Times and other newspaper clippings re nursing shortage in hospitals
- RNs City Wide, 1981-1985 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  Press release, "Statement by Mayor Edward I. Koch," re tentative agreement with NYS Nurses Association, October 3, 1985; list of Federation of Nurses/UFT municipal members by hospital; handwritten notes
- Update with Hospital Background, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  Lists of hospitals, associated unions, and contract expiration dates; newspaper clippings
- Visiting Nurse Association of Albany (1 of 2), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  Correspondence from NYS Nurses Association re representation election, collective bargaining agreement; petition to National Labor Relations Board; newspaper clippings; newsletters; flyers; press release, "Albany Visiting Nurses Ratify Contract; Strike Averted," April 5, 1988
- Visiting Nurse Association of Albany (2 of 2), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  Photograph of group in front of Visiting Nurse Association of Albany; computer disk; brochure, "Benedictine Registered Nurses: What's In It for You? Straight Answers to Some Common Questions about FNHP/NYSUT"; NLRB official secret ballot; Guidelines for Provision of Skilled Nursing Visits on a 24-Hour Basis"; Agreement between Visiting Nurse Association of Albany, Inc., and New York State Nurses Association, July 1, 1980-July 1, 1982, and January 1, 1985-December 31, 1987; FNHP 1986 National Survey of Hospital and Medical School Salaries, June 1987; Agreement for Hospital to Home among Albany Medical Center, St. Peter's Hospital, and Visiting Nurse Association of Albany, Inc., Albany County Department of Health, and Home Aide Service of Eastern New York, Inc.; on-call policies and procedures and related materials
- Arden Hill Hospital, 1979-1986 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  Hospital financial summary (annual report of charitable organization) for years ending December 31, 1984, 1983, 1982; photocopies of authorization cards; NLRB decision and direction of election re Arden Hill Hospital (employer) and Arden Hill Employees Federation, NYSUT, AFL-CIO (petitioner); letter from management urging rejection of union, April 18, 1986; draft of letter from organizers rebutting letter from management; organizing report form; lists of employees; handwritten notes
- Campaign Health and Hospitals Corporation, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  Folder of materials for 1982 municipal hospitals campaign: NYSUT and UFT correspondence, proposed budget, list of members of Federation of Nurses/UFT